Guide to the Irving S. Olds Collection of Naval and Other Historical Prints and Related Papers 1587-1960 PR 47
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Prints from the Olds Collection Donated by White & Case, 1761-1894; 2.63 Linear feet in flat files and one flat box
  - W&C Inventory No. 485. Etching on Newspaper: "The South Prospects of the City of New York of North America.", 1761 (Folder FF-36)
    "Engraved for The London Magazine 1761."
  - W&C Inventory No. 490. (Olds No. 43). Etching, reproduction, colored: "View of New York, From Weehawken.", 1839 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "London Published for the Proprietors by Geo. Virtue, 26 Ivy Lane, 1839." Title is also in French and German (?). Below etching to the left, "W.H. Bartlett." and to the right, "R. Wellis."
  - W&C Inventory No. 491. (Olds No. 561). Etching, reproduction, colored: "Light House near Caldwell's Landing. (Hudson River.)", 1838 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "London Published for the Proprietors by Geo. Virtue, 26 Ivy Lane, 1838." Below etching to the left, "W.H. Bartlett." and to the right, H. Adlard."
  - W&C Inventory No. 493. (Olds No. 1120). Etching, reproduction, colored: "4 Scenes: Surrender of Burgoyne; Evacuation of New York; McDonough's Victory; Canal Celebration.", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    There are four separate prints. All are drawn by J.L. Morton. Engravers are F. Humphreys, A. Jones, W.H. Dougal, and G.B. Ellis.
  - W&C Inventory No. 496. Engraving, reproduction: "George Washington after Gilbert Stuart.", undated (Folder FF-34)
    Engraved by William Edgar Marshall from the original portrait in the Boston Athaneaum painted by Gilbert Stuart.
  - W&C Inventory No. 498. (Olds No. 537). Engraving, colored: "Landing of Hendrick Hudson.", undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "From the original picture by R.W. Weir in the possession of Gulian C. Verplanck, Esq." Published by Martin Johnson & Company, New York.
  - W&C Inventory No. 499. (Olds No. 61). Print, colored: "Federal Hall, Wall Street and Trinity Church, New York, in 1789.", 1879 (Folder FF-34)
    Published by M.C. Hyde from a contemporary print, 1879.
  - W&C Inventory No. 500. (Olds No. 524). Engraving, colored: "Last Words of Captain Nathan Hale, the Hero-Martyr of the American Revolution.", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "Designed by F.O. C. Darley, engraved by A.H. Ritchie, and Published Exclusively for Subscribers to the Adventures and Achievements of Americans." Below engraving is a short description of Hale's execution.
  - W&C Inventory No. 507. (Olds No. 733). Reproduction: "Paul Jones the Pirate.", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    No publisher, artist, engraver given. Standing figure of Jones over a cannon with a sword in one hand and a gun in the other.
  - W&C Inventory No. 508. (Olds No. 510). Engraving: "Journée de Lexington", 1784? (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "A Paris chez Mr. Godefrey, rue de Frances Bourgeois, Porte St. Michel, et chez Mr. Ponce, rue de St. Hyacinthe, au No. 19. A.P.D.R." "Del. et Grave par F. Godefrey" Below engraving is an explanation of the Battle of Lexington (French). [1784].
  - W&C Inventory No. 511. (Olds No. 378). Engraving, colored, newspaper reproduction: "View of the City of Algiers.", undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "For the American Universal Magazine" at center top above colored engraving.
  - W&C Inventory No. 513. (Olds No. 48). Etching, reproduction: "Mansion House, (Bunkers,) Broadway, New York.", undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "Burton, del.; Archer, sc." New York, Bourne Publishers. Upper right corner, "Plate 5th."
  - W&C Inventory No. 514. (Olds No. 111). Etching, reproduction, colored: :Decatur's Conflict with the Algerine at Tripoli. Reuben Ames interposing his head to save the Life of his Commander.", 1877 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "From the original painting by Chappel, in the possession of the Publisher." Johnson & Miles, publishers.
  - W&C Inventory No. 515. (Olds No. 755). Etching, reproduction: "Paul Jones", 1875 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Adolphe Varin, engraver. Full face portrait of John Paul Jones.
  - W&C Inventory No. 517. Etching, reproduction: "Nathan Clifford.", undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Full-face portrait of Clifford by Albert Rosenthal.
  - W&C Inventory No. 518. (Olds No. 535). Etching, reproduction, colored: "The First Landing of the Pilgrims, 1620.", 1856 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Published by Martin Johnson & Co., New York. Painted by Charles Isnay and engraved by T. Philibrown.
  - W&C Inventory No. 519: (Olds No. 1066). Newspaper article print, colored: "Action of the Constitution and Guerriere", undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Engraving on page "309" of American Magazine of Useful Knowledge. Page 310 is on reverse. Below engraving are notes from the official report of the action between the Constitution and the Guerriere.
  - W&C Inventory No. 520. (Olds No. 49). Lithograph, reproduction, colored: "Mansion House, (Bunkers,) [39] Broadway, New-York, in 1831, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "Lith. for D.T. Valentine's Manual, 1855." "By George Hayward, 120 Water Street, N.Y." Depicts residence of General George Washington during the 2nd. Session of the First Congress.
  - W&C Inventory No. 522. (Olds No. 26). Etching, reproduction, colored: "View of the Bay and Harbour of New-York, From the Battery.", 1830 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "Drawn (C. Burton) and engraved (Wm. D. Smith) for the New York Mirror, 1830.
  - W&C Inventory No. 523. (Olds No. 558). Etching, reproduction, colored: "Crow-Nest From Bull Hill. (Hudson River.).", 1838 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "London Published for the Proprietors by Geo. Virtue, 26 Ivy Lane, 1838." Below etching to the left, "W.H. Bartlett." and to the right, "G.R. Richardson."
  - W&C Inventory No. 524. Etching, reproduction, colored: "New York Bay. (From the Telegraph Station.)", 1838 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "London Published for the Proprietors by Geo. Virtue, 26 Ivy Lane, 1838." Under etching to the left, "W.H. Bartlett." and to the right, "R. Wallis."
  - W&C Inventory No. 525. (Olds No. 25). Etching, reproduction, colored: "Street View No.2. Wall Street.", undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Drawn & Engraved for the New York Mirror. C. Burton. Del. W. Hoagland. Sc. "Printed by Smith..." in lower right margin.
  - W&C Inventory No. 526. (Olds No. 10). Engraving, reproduction: "Incendie de New-York", 1782 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "Dessiné par le Barbier, Peintre du Roi; grave par L. Halbou sculp." Pencil at bottom right margin "avant la tomaison"
  - W&C Inventory No. 527. (Olds No. 967). Painting reproduction: "Capitulation of Algiers.", 1894 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    The print depicts men around a table signing a document. In the background the ship placard, "Guerriere". Presumably the Treaty of Algiers is being signed. "H. Ditzle" signature is shown on the print. "Copyrighted 1894 by G.B." is centered on top in the margin.
  - W&C Inventory No. 529. (Olds No. 523). Lithograph, colored: "The American General Lee taken Prisoner by Lieutenant Colonel Harcourt of the English Army, in Morris County, New Jersey, 1776.", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Hamilton, delin. No information on publisher given.
  - W&C Inventory No. 530. (Olds No. 529). Etching, reproduction, colored: "The Surrender of Lord Cornwallis (Lieutenant-General of the British Army in North America) to General Washington & Count de Rochambeau, on the 19th of Octr. 1781__whereby the Posts of York-Town & Glouchester in Virginia, were then given up to the combined Forces of America & France.", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Hamilton, delin. and Thorton, sculp.
  - W&C Inventory No. 531. Etching, reproduction: "The State Watchman.", undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Oval, full face, portrait of a gentleman in a military coat. Black and white.
  - W&C Inventory No. 532. (Olds No. 565). Engraving, reproduction, colored: "Rail-Road Scene, Little Falls. (Valley of the Mohawk.).", 1838 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "London Published for the Proprietors by Geo. Virtue, 26 Ivy Lane, 1838." Below etching to the left, "W.H. Bartlett." and to the right, "R. Sands."
  - W&C Inventory No. 533. (Olds No. 99). Engraving, reproduction: "Cap't. Sterrett in the Sch'r. Enterprise paying tribute to Tripoli, August 1801., 1816 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Engraved after painting by M. Corne. From "The Naval Temple", Boston, 1816.
  - W&C Inventory No. 534. (Olds No. 351). Engraving, reproduction, colored:"Triumphant return of the American Squadron under Com. Bainbridge from the Mediterranean 1815", undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    M. Corne del. Printed by Samuel Maverick N.Y. W.S. Leney sc. On back of engraving appears to be signature of "James J. Woolsey" and other notations.
  - W&C Inventory No. 535. (Olds No. 531). Lithograph, colored: "Surrender of Cornwallis, at York-Town Va. Oct. 1871.", 1845 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Lith. & Pub. by N. Currier, 2 Spruce St. N.Y. Key below lithograph.
  - W&C Inventory No. 536. (Olds No. 552). Etching, reproduction: "Palissades Naturelles de l'Hudson.", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    "Etats-Unis" and "26" above etching in margin.
  - W&C Inventory No. 538. Etching, reproduction, colored: "The Temple Church, As Restored", 1828 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Drawn by Thos. H. Shepherd. Engraved by J. Carter. Published Aug. 16, 1828 by Jones & Co. 3 Acton Place, Kingsland Road, London.
  - W&C Inventory No. 540. (Olds No. 89). Woodcut, colored: "Engagement Between the Bon Homme and Serapis; The Former Commanded by Paul Jones, and the Latter by Captain Richard Pearson.", undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    No artist, engraver, publisher, or date given.
  - W&C Inventory No. 542. (Olds No. 500). Etching, reproduction: "A Representation of the Medal presented by the United States to Thomas Truxtun Esquire...", undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Full title: "A Representation of the Medal presented by the United States to Thomas Truxtun Esquire, and a copy of the Resolution of Congress. The lower circle is the Obverse side of the Medal (U.S. Frigate Constellation and French Ship La Venegeance)". Artists for medal are given but unreadable. No artist, publisher, date given for print.
  - W&C Inventory No. 543. (Olds No. 27). Engraving, colored: "View of the Bowling-Green, Broadway.", 1830 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "Drawn and engraved for the New York Mirror. 1830." "Drawn by Davis." "V. Balch, sc."
  - W&C Inventory No. 544. (Olds No. 24). Engraving, colored: "Street Views No. 1. Park Row.", 1830 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "Drawn and Engraved for the New York Mirror. 1830." "Drawn by C. Burton." "Engraved by Wm. D. Smith."
  - W&C Inventory No. 545. (Olds No. 548). Engraving, colored: "Capture of the City of Washington", 1815 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Published by J&J Cundee, Albion Press, London.
  - W&C Inventory No. 546. (Olds No. 536). Engraving, colored: "Landing of Roger Williams.", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    "From the original picture in the possession of the Publishers (Martin Johnson & Co., New York). Painted by Alonzo Chappel and engraved by G.R. Hall.
  - W&C Inventory No. 548. Newspaper Print: "The United States and Macedonian.", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Page (421/422) from American Magazine of Useful Knowledge.
  - W&C Inventory No. 549. (Olds No. 521). Engraving, colored: "The State Watchman discovered by the Genius of Britain studying plans for the Reduction of America.", 1781 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "Pubd by I. Jones, 10 Dec. 1781".
  - W&C Inventory No. 550. (Olds No. 588). Engraved portrait: "George Washington EQer, Général en Chef de l'Armée Anglo-Amériquaine, nommé Dictateur par le Congrès en Fevrier 1777.", undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "A Pris chez Esnauts et Rapilly, rue St. Jacques, a la Ville de Coutances. A.P.D.R." Three-quarter face portrait with hat and sword.
  - W&C Inventory No. 551. Etching, reproduction. "Samuel Chase.", undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Etching by Albert Rosenthal, 1890. Phila.
  - W&C Inventory No. 553. Lithograph, colored: "The Battle of New-Orleans, Fought Jany. 8th. 1815.", 1842 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Lith. and published by N. Currier.
  - W&C Inventory No. 554. (Olds No. 58). Lithographs, colored: "Four Views of New York City", undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Four lithographs of views of New York, framed together. (a) "Wall Street at William Street, looking West, 1825." Lithographed by McSpedon & Baker. (b) "Federal Hall and the Verplanck Mansion Wall Street, 1789." Drawn by David Grim. Lithographed by G. Hayward. For Valentine's Manual, 1856. (c) "New York & City Banks and the McEvers Mansion, Wall St. in 1800. The Residence of Gen. Knyphausen during the Revolution." Lithographed by G. Hayward. For Valentine's Manual, 1856. (d) "Broad Street. (Custom House in the Distance.)" Lithographed by G. Hayward. For Valentine's Manual, 1853.
  - W&C Inventory No. 557. (Olds No. 539). Engraving: "William Penn's Treaty with the Indians (Duplicate).", 1775 (Folder FF-38)
  - W&C Inventory No. 560. (Olds No. 338). Music Score: "To Commodore Charles Stewart. "Old Ironsides" This Song is Cheerfully Inscribed by his friend. The Author.", 1856 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    The cover has a colored lithograph of three ships - The Cyane, The Constitution, and The Levant. T.P. Otter, del.; T. Sinclair, lith.,Phila. Lee & Walker of Philadelphia is the publisher. The Music is "Old Ironsides" by Charles T. Frey with words by Brainard Williamson.
  - W&C Inventory No. 561. (Olds No. 583). Engraving, colored: "Conclusion de la Campagne Liberte de 1781 en Virginie.", undated (Folder FF-34)
  - W&C Inventory No. 562. (Olds No. 646). Etching, reproduction, colored: "Perry's Victory on Lake Erie - after Birch.", undated (Folder FF-38)
    Painted by T. Birch. Engraved by A. Lawson. Published by W.H. Smith, Philadelphia.
  - W&C Inventory No. 563. (Olds No. 506). Stone Lithograph, colored: "View of the Harlem River #4.", 1852 (Folder FF-38)
    Pub. & Lith. by Currier & Ives. From nature and on stone, F.F. Palmer. The High Bridge is in the distance.
  - W&C Inventory No. 566. (Olds No. 643). Stone Lithograph, colored: "H.M.S. Shannon Carrying by Boarding the American Frigate Chesapeake. View No. 3.", undated (Folder FF-35)
    "Painted by J.G. Schetky, Esq. & On Stone by L. Haghe. ... Designed by Capt. R.H. King, R.N." Published by Smith, Elder & Co., London. "No. 3" centered above lithograph.
  - W&C Inventory No. 567. (Olds No. 1073). Print, reproduction: "List of American and British Naval Fleets to 1813.", undated (Folder FF-37)
    No publisher given.
  - W&C Inventory No. 568. (Olds No. 228). Engraving, colored: "Action between Chesapeake and Shannon.", 1816 (Folder FF-35)
    Engraving depicts a silver platter, manufactured by S. Hougham & Co, commemorating the battle between the Chesapeake and the Shannon. Engraving was executed by Henry Meyer. Published in London by the proprietor on December 2, 1816.
  - W&C Inventory No. 569. (Olds No. 983). Engraving: "Boat Transporting Major John Andre.", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    The print is an exact copy of the drawing by John Andre in 1780.
  - W&C Inventory No. 570. (Olds No. 1088). Print, colored: "Various Naval Actions of War of 1812., 'We have Met the Enemy and They are Ours.'", 1816 (Folder FF-35)
    No artist, engraver, or publisher given.
  - W&C Inventory No. 571. Lithograph, colored: "Benjamin Franklin. Statesman and Philosopher.", 1847 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - W&C Inventory No. 572. Lithograph, reproduction, colored: "Benjamin Franklin (grey hair/grey suit).", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Three-quarter face portrait of Franklin. Vanlee, pinxt. and P.M. Alix, sculp.
  - W&C Inventory No. 573. (Olds No. 337). Aquatint: "View of Action Between U.S. Frigate Constitution & The British Ships Levant & Cyane.", undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Published by S.C. Atkinson.
  - W&C Inventory No. 576. (Olds No. 915). Engraving, colored: "View of New York. From Brooklyn Heights.", 1849 (Folder FF-34)
    Lith. & Pub. N. Currier. Palmer, del. Buildings on the Manhattan side noted below engraving.
  - W&C Inventory No. 577. (Olds No. 260). Engraving, colored: "Perry's Victory.", undated (Folder FF-35)
  - W&C Inventory No. 578. (Olds No. 641). Stone Lithograph, colored: "H.M.S. Shannon commencing the Battle with the American Frigate Chesapeake - after J.G. Schetky. View No. 1.", undated (Folder FF-35)
    "Painted by J.G. Schetky, Esq. & On Stone by L. Haghe. ... Designed by R.H. King, R.N." Published by Smith, Elder & Co., London. "No. 1" cntered above lithograph.
  - W&C Inventory No. 579. Stone Lithograph, colored: "Capture of the Chesapeake by the Shannon - After Schetky, J.G.", undated (Folder FF-35)
    "Painted by J.G. Schetky, Esq. & On Stone by L. Haghe. ... Designed by Capt. R.H. King, R.N." Published by Smith, Elder & Co., London. "No. 4" centered abovetop of lithograph.
  - W&C Inventory No. 580. (Olds No. 625). Engraving, colored: "U.S. Frigate Constitution Capturing His Britannic Majesty's Frigate Guerriere - after Birch.", 1813 (Folder FF-38)
    Painted by T. Birch. Engraved by C. Tiebout. Published by James Webster, Philadelphia.
  - W&C Inventory No. 581. (Olds No. 578). Engraving, colored: "Map of Virginia.", undated (Folder FF-34)
    "Ex officina Guiljelmi Blaeuw."
  - W&C Inventory No. 582. Lithograph, colored: "Map of Virginia to Florida." (Folder FF-34)
    No information on publisher, engraver, artist given.
  - W&C Inventory No. 583. Photogravure, colored: "First Recognition of American Flag by Foreign Government - after Moran.", undated (Folder FF-37)
    "Painted by Edward Moran, copyright 1898. ... Blechinger & Leykauf, Vienna, Hel. & Imp."
  - W&C Inventory No. 584. (Olds No. 977). Engraving, colored: "The Attack on Fort Moultrie, Sullivan's Island, South Carolina, on June 28, 1776.", 1858 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Page 408/407 from Harper's Weekly., June 26, 1858.
  - W&C Inventory No. 4302. (Olds No. 519). Engraving: "The Manner in which the American Colonies Declared themselves Independent of the King of England, throughout the different Provinces, on July 4, 1776.", 1781-1783 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Hand-colored engraving by Noble (Hamilton delin.) produced for Barnard's "New Complete and Authentic History of England", London: Edward Barnard, 1781-1783.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 610). Engraving, with aquatint: "Perpetual calendar with profile of George Washington in a circle with background of an American flag.", 1895 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Inscribed: E.G. 1895. Catalogue of The Edwin Babcock Holden Collection of Rare American and Fine Engravings, American Art Galleries, New York, beginning April 18, 1910; Lot 243, wherein the calendar is described as scarce.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 350 (a) & (b)). Aquatint: "United States Squadron under Com. Bainbridge returning Triumphant from the Mediterranean in 1815." and Mezzotint, colored: "Wm. Bainbridge.", 1838, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Aquatint: J.B. Fanning Des.; G.G. Smith Sc.(1795-1878). Second state, omitting original copyright data of entry by A. Bowen on November 25, 1815. Illustration from a late edition of "The Naval Monument", published at Boston, 1838. Mezzotint: After Gilbert Stuart (1755-1828), engraved by John Sartain (1807-1897).
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 435). Hand-colored Stipple Engraving: "Naval Heroes: Bainbridge, Lawrence, Decatur, Porter, MacDonough." (group of five bust portraits), c. 1814 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Reed & Stiles, sc. Frontispiece of "Life and Character of Stephen Decatur", by S. Waldo Putnam, Middletown, CT., 1821; also an illustration in "The Life of Oliver Hazard Perry", by John M. Niles, Hartford, CT., 1820.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 590?). Etching with hand-coloring: "Washington (Georges), President de la Republique des Etats-unis d'Amerique du Nord + 1799.", 1838 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    After portrait of Washington by Charles Willson Peale. Dessine par Girardet; Tableau du temps; Grave par Wolff. Plate from Charles Gavard's Galeries historiques de Versailles. Published Paris 1838.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds 652a?). Engraving, hand colored: "MacDonough's Victory on Lake Champlain.", undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Inscribed "A.Hill" and "Peirce, SC." in plate.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 28). Steel Engraving: "View of the Old City Hall, Wall St. In the year 1789.", 1850 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Drawn by Diedrich Knickerbocker, Jr. [Diedrich Knickerbocker was a pseudonym for the author (but not artist) Washington Irving, who in other publications gave credit to Robert Hinshelwood (American, 1812-1879)] Engraved on steel by Hatch & Smillie. Drawn and engraved for the New York Mirror. Printed by J. & G. Neale, 1850.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds 588). Engraving: "George Washington Eqer. General en Chief de l'Armee Anglo-Ameriquaine, nomme Dictateur par le Congres en Fevrier, 1777.", c. 1780 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Published by Esnauts et Rapily, Paris.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds 1022). Lithograph, hand-colored: "Passed Midshipman. U.S. Navy.", 1840 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    From life on stone by A. Hoffy (American, 1790-1860). Printed by P.S. Duval, Philadelphia. From Full Dress: U.S. Military Magazine - Army & Navy, Vol. 1st p14, 1840.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 1048). Engraving, hand-colored: "Mount Vernon, 1874." (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Drawn by Theo R. Davis (American, 1840-1894). Harper's Weekly 197, February 28, 1874. Published by Harper and Brothers.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 1033). Ink on paper drawing: "Commodore Perry in the Niagara Breaking the British Line-of-battle Lake Erie, Sept. 10, 1813.", undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Drawn by J.O. davidson (American, 1853-1893).
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 586). Engraving, hand-colored: "Washington, Generalissime des Etats unis de l'Amerique.", 1780 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Grave par Chevillet (French, 1729-1802). Dessine par Bounieu d'apres un Tableau fourni par M. le Marquis de la Fayette. First state after painting by Charles Willson Peale.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 1090). Facsimile collotype of an ink wash drawing: "A View of the French Fleet 24 Sail of the Line under Count De Grasse coming round Cape Henry out of the Chesapeake while the English Fleet of 19 Sail of the Line under Rear Admiral Graves were standing into attack them, 5th September 1781. [Battle of the Virginia Capes, 5 September 1781]", undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    In the Collection of National Maritime Museum, Greenwich, England. By an unidentified hand [Catalogue No. PAH4074]. Reproduced by The Chiswick Press, London.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 512?). Etching, hand-colored: "Battle of Bunker's Hill.", 1832 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Designed, Drawn & Engraved by J. Baker. Published 1832 by Humphrey Phelps, New York.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 1012). Lithograph: "Combat Naval. Episode de la Guerre des Etats-Unis contre Angleterre.", c. 1840 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Drawn by Perrot (French, 1808-1841). Paris, V. Delarue. From portfolio: Etudes de Marines par F'd Perrot.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 516). Engraving: "The Death of General Montgomery at Quebec/ La Mort du General Montgomery devant Quebec.", 1808 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Engraved by Christian Wilhelm Ketterlinus. Painted by John Trumbull (American, 1756-1843). Published 1808 by John Trumbull, New York. Printed by Andrew Maverick.
  - W&C Inventory No Number. (Olds No. 658). Engraving. "South east view of Sackett's Harbour", 1815 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Thomas Birch, delt. Engraved & printed by Gavitt & Duthie after an engraving by William Strickland
  - W&C Inventory No Number. "Battle Monument, Baltimore", 1830s? (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Lithograph of Pendleton, New York. Henry Walton
  - Labels from backing of prints, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)